Nancy Hamilton Papers, 1862-1992
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS AND CORRESPONDENCE
  - Correspondence
    - American Foundation for the Blind, 1952-71, undated, [see also SERIES II. HELEN KELLER IN HER STORY - Distribution and showings and Financial and legal matters, and SERIES III. SUBJECTS - Katharine Cornell] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Burke, Billie, 1954-58, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Corbally, Winny, 1961-64 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Edwards, Douglas, 1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and Mamie, 1953-54, [see also SERIES II. HELEN KELLER IN HER STORY - Development and production] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Elkins, Cyril, 1954-55, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gore-Booth, Paul, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hayes, Helen, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Henny, Nella Braddy and Keith, 1954-74, [see also SERIES II. HELEN KELLER IN HER STORY - Development and production] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Keller, Helen, 1954-60 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Mack, Rebecca, 1953-55, [see also SERIES II. HELEN KELLER IN HER STORY - Development and production] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thomson, Robert J., 1958-60, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Tyson, Katharine Keller and Mildred Keller, 1952-61, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified, 1953-58, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- SERIES II. HELEN KELLER IN HER STORY
  - Development and production
    - Source materials for the film
      - Correspondence and notes
        - Eisenhower, President Dwight D., film appearance, 1953, [see also SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Henney, Nella Braddy, consultant, 1952-54, [see also SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Mack, Rebecca, 1953, [see also SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Wood, Richard Carver, director, 1952-54 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952-53, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous printed material about blindness, 1933-34, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Still photographs of Deliverance 1919, [See SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND NEGATIVES] (Box 1)
    - Scripts
      - Braille, [See SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
      - General, 1952-53, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
      - Shot sheet, 1952-53, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
      - Narration
        - Katharine Cornell, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Helen Keller, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Distribution and showings
      - Correspondence, notes, and clippings
        - ABC News, 1979-80 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - American Foundation for the Blind and American Foundation for the Overseas Blind, 1953-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Birmingham and Tuscumbia, Alabama, 1954, [see also Promotion - Miscellaneous - Clippings] (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Distribution, 1953-58, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Fitelson and Mayers, legal counsel, 1952-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Information Productions, Inc, agent, 1954-56, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - International showings, 1954-60, undated, [see also Helen Keller trip to Norway and Sweden] (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - Louis de Rochemont Associates, Inc., agent, 1956-59, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Scottish Film Council, 1958-59, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Seventy-fifth birthday, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - United States Information Agency, 1952-58, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Helen Keller trip to Norway and Sweden: correspondence, memos, and itinerary, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous printed materials, typescript, and clippings, 1952-60, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Financial and legal matters
      - Correspondence, receipts, and financial statements
        - Albert Margolies & Co., Inc., 1954-58, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Information Productions, Inc., 1953-56 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Louis de Rochemont Associates, Inc., 1956-59 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Nathan W. Levin, 1952-59
          - Correspondence and receipts, 1952-59, undated (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
          - Statements of receipts and disbursements, 1952-57 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952-58, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - American Foundation for the Blind
        - Correspondence, 1953-58, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Contracts, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Promotion
      - Film opening and display: notes and sponsor lists, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Arlene Francis Show, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous promotion
        - Correspondence, 1953-58, undated (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
        - Clippings, 1954-55, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Printed materials, press releases, and notes, 1954-56, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Katharine Cornell interview: correspondence, and typescript copy of article, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Swedenborgian Foundation, 1953-55 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Reviews
        - Index, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - Clippings and articles, 1954-58 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Letters of appreciation, 1953-61, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Awards and tributes
      - Academy Award
        - Correspondence
          - Congratulatory, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
          - Miscellaneous, 1955-63, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
        - Printed material, 1956, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
        - Kinescope, [see SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS] (Box 5)
        - Oscar statuette and certificate [see SERIES VI: OVERSIZE MATERIALS (Box 5)
      - Scholastic Teacher award, 1957, [see also SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND NEGATIVES] (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Other awards, 1956-69 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- SERIES III. SUBJECT FILES
  - Blindness, 1952-55 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cornell, Katharine
    - American Foundation for the Blind trusteeship
      - Migel Award, 1957-64, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1952-72 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - American Foundation for Overseas Blind, 1964-72
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1952-72 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - World Crusade, 1958-68, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Arlene Francis radio program/interview, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, notes, and printed material, 1966-68, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - Keller, Helen, 1943-53, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1944-72, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Forbes, Brenda, 1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Keller, Helen
    - American Foundation for the Blind bequest, 1969, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Articles and clippings, 1888-1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Awards and tributes
      - Helen Keller Memorial Fund, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Rotary Club Award, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Washington Cathedral sculpture dedication, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Biography proposals
      - Endore, Guy, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Hamilton, Nancy, 1954, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Martin, Ralph, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Birthday celebrations, [see also Clippings and articles]
      - Seventy-fifth, 1954-55 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Eightieth and eighty-fifth, 1960, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1944-59 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Medical information, 1961-64 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Obituaries and funeral service, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Radio broadcasts: scripts, 1937(?), 1943 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Speeches and writings, 1894-1952, undated, [see also SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND NEGATIVES] (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Tours of Latin America, the Far East, Europe, and Africa, 1952-55, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Levy, Adele, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Miracle Worker: correspondence, clippings, and program, 1957-60 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Nightingale, Florence: anonymous script, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Smith College: gift of film and report on footage, 1965-66, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sullivan, Anne: Centennial, 1965-66, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Thomson, Polly, 1953-62, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND NEGATIVES, [see also SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
  - Hamilton, Nancy, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Keller, Helen
    - Bust by Jo Davidson, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Alone
      - 1887 - circa 1910 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - circa 1911-65 (Box 8)
      - With others
        - Bell, Alexander Graham, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - Cornell, Katharine, 1956-57 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - Keller, Mildred, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - Sullivan, Anne, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - Thompson, Polly, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Keller Homestead, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Martha Graham and dancers, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sullivan, Anne, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Book titles, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Photographic stills from Deliverance and from Helen Keller In Her Story,, 1919, 1955 (Box 9)
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
  - Film footage (kinescope) of Nancy Hamilton receiving her Oscar, 1956 (Box 10)
    [original closed until reformatted]
  - Audiotape (1 open reel), Helen Keller at the Library of Congress, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Helen Keller In Her Story, [see also SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
    - Videotape (VHS) of documentary, HTV Inc. 1992 (Box 10)
    - Sound recordings [originals closed until reformatted]
      - Audiotapes (2 open reel), film sound track, 1954 (Box 10)
      - Audiotape (1 open reel), musical sound track, (taken from Private Record made by Budd Lewis from original sound track of film), undated (Box 10)
      - Phonograph records (LP 33) (Box 10)
        - Katharine Cornell test recording of narration, 1953 (Box 10)
        - Sound track narrated by Katharine Cornell, undated (Box 10)
    - Research copies of film footage (9 DVDs): outtakes and trims, 2006, [see list in Appendix] (Box 11)
    - Research copies of soundtrack (1 CD), 2006, [See list in Appendix] (Box 11)
    - Master copies of above (10 Digital Betamax tapes), 2006 (Box 12-13)
      [CLOSED, use research copies]
    - Original film footage and soundtrack from documentary, Helen Keller In Her Story (1955) (132 canisters)
- SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Photographs (Box 12-13)
    - Helen Keller, Polly Thomson, and two unidentified men (2), undated (Box 14)
    - Helen Keller and Polly Thomson, undated (Box 14)
    - Helen Keller and Anne Sullivan, undated (Box 14)
    - Clipping: "The Silent Star of the Silent Drama," undated (Box 14)
    - Helen Keller with Martha Graham and two dancers (2), undated (Box 14)
    - Portrait of Helen Keller in academic robe inscribed to Nancy Hamilton from Alexander Clayton, undated (Box 14)
  - Promotion for Helen Keller In Her Story: "Never has a film been so Widely Acclaimed …," n.d (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook of Helen Keller's seventy- fifth birthday tribute from CBS, 1954 (Box 14)
  - Golden Reel Award: plaque, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Braille script for film, 1952 (Box 14)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Science Certificate, 1955 (Box 14)
  - Oscar statuette (currently on display in Reading Room) (Box 14)